lowcostholidays.com 2017-09-10

# Privacy Policy - loveholidays

#### loveholidays takes your privacy seriously

loveholidays understands and respects the importance of your privacy and we are committed to safeguarding your personal information. 

Any personal information you provide to us including and similar to your name, address, telephone number and email address will not be released, sold, or rented to any entities or individuals outside of loveholidays except where required by us to process your booking and to ensure that your travel arrangements run smoothly and meet your requirements. Our representatives may sometimes follow up, either by e-mail, phone, fax or mail, to people who have registered their details and we may periodically send promotional e-mail about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the e-mail address which you have provided. 

We take full responsibility for ensuring that proper security measures are in place to protect your information. We must pass the information on to the relevant suppliers of your travel arrangements such as your tour operator, airlines, hotels, transport companies etc. The information may also be provided to security or credit checking companies, public authorities such as customs/immigration if required by them, or as required by law. We may need to disclose our customer list including any personal information relating to you to a third party who acquires or attempts to acquire all or substantially all of the asset/ stock in our company or our website. 

Where your holiday is outside the European Economic Area (EEA), controls on data protection in your destination may not be as strong as the legal requirements in this country. We will not however, pass any information onto any person not responsible for part of your travel arrangements. This applies to any sensitive information that you give to us such as details of any disabilities, or dietary/religious requirements. (If we cannot pass this information to the relevant suppliers, whether in the EEA or not, we cannot provide your booking. In making this booking, you consent to this information being passed on to the relevant persons.)

Usually your tour operator or other principal will pass this information onto their suppliers once we have provided it to them. The tour operator or other principal's use of your information is subject to their policy, both in respect of your booking and any future marketing, and is their responsibility. Please ask either us or them for a copy of this if you would like to see it. 

#### CREDIT & DEBIT CARD DETAILS

All credit card information and personal information is encrypted as it is passed between your browser and our website. When you make a booking your initial payment is cleared using the information you provide. Your credit card number is not held in our database. All encryption is performed using at least 128 bits making it virtually impossible to decrypt without the necessary decryption key. 

#### MONITORING

To ensure that we carry out your instructions accurately, to help improve our service and in the interest of security, we may monitor and/or record: (1) your telephone calls; (2) customer activities using CCTV recording equipment in and around our premises; and (3) customer transactions and activities on our website. All recordings are and shall remain our sole property. 

#### OTHER WEBSITES

Our website may contain links to enable you to visit other websites of interest easily. However, once you have used these links to leave our site you should note that we do not have any control over that other web site. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this Privacy Statement. You should exercise caution and look at the Privacy Statement applicable to the website in question. 

#### WHAT CAN I DO?

You are entitled to a copy of your information held by us. If you would like to see this please ask us. [We may make a small charge for providing this to you]. 

If you do not agree to our use of the information as set out above, you should inform us as soon as possible by writing to us at loveholidays, The Triangle, 4th Floor South Side, 5-17 Hammersmith Grove, London, W6 0LG. 

In accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998, you may ask us in writing for a copy of the information we hold about you (for which we may charge an administration fee) and to correct any inaccuracies in your information. We aim to respond to you within 21 days from the date of request. 

You can also choose not to provide us with some of the information we request, however as a result we may not be able to complete your booking. 

#### OPT-OUT POLICY

Subscribers can opt out of receiving further information from us at any time. You will also be given a fast and easy option of opting out on all communications. 

#### COOKIES

Please note that in order for us to provide you with optimum service, we use ‘Cookies’ on our website. 

**What are cookies?**

A "cookie" is a small data text file that is placed in your browser and allows loveholidays to recognise you each time you visit this site (customisation etc). Cookies themselves do not contain any personal information, and loveholidays does not use cookies to collect personal information. Cookies may also be used to pass information between websites owned by loveholidays. Cookies will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the "lifetime" of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number. 

Two types of cookies are used on this web site - session cookies, which are temporary cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser until you leave the site, and persistent cookies, which remain in the cookie file of your browser for much longer (though how long will depend on the lifetime of the specific cookie). 

Cookies allow us to obtain information regarding users of our site which essentially helps us to provide you with a better user experience and tailor our services to your individual needs. We may collect information such as your IP address, online activity, web browser details and online activity. We will not however collect or store any of your passwords or other highly sensitive data. 

**By using our website with your browser settings adjusted to accept all cookies, we will take this to mean that you want to use our products and services, and that you consent to our use of cookies and other technologies as described in this Policy.**

**Browser settings:** Most browsers have options that allow the visitor to control whether the browser will accept cookies, reject cookies, or notify the visitor each time a cookie is sent. You may elect to reject cookies by adjusting your browser's settings, but doing so will limit the range of features available to the visitor on our site and most other major websites that use cookies.   

We use the following types of cookies on our website:  

#### Category 1: strictly necessary cookies 

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the website. Without these cookies services you have asked for, like shopping baskets or e-billing, cannot be provided. 

#### Category 2: performance cookies 

These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies don’t collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. It is only used to improve how a website works. 

#### Category 3: Functionality Cookies 

These cookies are used to recognise you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region). 

#### Category 4: Targeting or Advertising Cookies 

These cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. They are usually placed by advertising networks with our permission. They remember that you have visited a website and this information is shared with other organisations such as advertisers. Quite often targeting or advertising cookies will be linked to site functionality provided by the other organisation. 

**By using our website, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device.**  
**Further information:** to find out more information about cookies, please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

#### UPDATES & CHANGES 

As our privacy statement may change due to developments in the law we encourage you to re read this from time to time so you are aware of any changes in how we gather and use your personal information. Any changes to this Policy will be either posted on our website, brochure and/or made available on request. 

Last Updated: March 2015 

#### WEBSITE TERMS OF USE

This website is owned and operated by loveholidays (“the Company”). Access to and use of any information on this website is conditional on your acceptance of these website terms and conditions (“the Conditions”). We recommend you read them carefully and print out and keep a copy of them for your future reference. If you do not wish to accept any part of these Conditions then you may not use our website. 

Please Note:  
When you visit our website or send e-mails to us, you are communicating electronically. We will also communicate with you by e-mail. You agree that all notices, agreements, disclosures and other communications that we provide to you electronically satisfy any requirement that such communications be in writing. 

By using this website, you warrant to us that: 

  1. You will not use this website or any material or information on it for any purpose that is unlawful or prohibited by these Conditions; 
  2. You are at least 18 years old and have the legal authority to use this website in accordance with these Conditions; 
  3. You agree to be financially responsible for all charges, fees and other sums of whatever nature which arise out of your use of this website; 
  4. All information that you provide about yourself and about anyone else shall be true and accurate. 

You must not link (including deep linking) to our website or access, monitor or copy any content or information of this website using any robot, spider, scraper or other automated means or any manual process for any purpose without our prior written agreement. 

Copyright Notice  
All content of this website (such as text, graphics, logos, button icons, images, audio clips, digital downloads, data compilations and software) is our exclusive property or that of our content suppliers (if applicable) and is, unless specifically stated otherwise, protected by copyright or similar ownership rights. It is published by us and may not be reproduced other than by downloading and viewing on a single computer and/or printing a single hard copy, for private purposes only. It is not to be otherwise reproduced, transmitted, made available on a network or used to create derivative works without our prior written consent. All rights are reserved.

The trade marks, logos and service marks shown on our website, unless otherwise specified, are our intellectual property. No rights are granted to use any of them without our prior written consent. 

Booking Conditions   
All bookings made on this website are subject to our booking conditions in addition to these Conditions. We recommend that you read our booking conditions carefully and print out and keep a copy of them for your future reference. 

Website Content  
We are an English registered Company. Our business and the services we offer are governed by the applicable laws of England and Wales except where otherwise stated in our booking conditions. No warranties, promises and/or representations of any kind, express or implied, are given as to the accuracy or completeness of any of the material or information contained on this website (in accordance with English law or with any laws of any other country) or as to the nature, standard, suitability or otherwise of any services offered by us or on our behalf.

We shall not be liable for any loss or damage or other sum or claim of any nature whatsoever (direct, indirect, consequential or other) which arises, directly or indirectly, in connection with this website.

The information contained on this website may contain technical inaccuracies and typographical and other errors. The information on these pages may be updated from time to time and may at times be out of date. If any price or other information is obviously incorrect, we will not be bound by it. You must ensure you check all details of the chosen arrangements (including the price) with us at the time of booking.

Occasionally, we may upload traveller reviews, blogs and recommendations on to our website. Such reviews and blogs are the personal opinions of the author of said content and not that of the Company. We take no responsibility and accept no liability in relation to these reviews, blogs, recommendations or other similar content on the website, or any resulting acts, omissions or losses incurred.

This website may contain links to other websites. Except where they belong to us, such other websites are not under our control or maintained by us. We are not responsible for the content of such websites. We provide these links for your convenience only but do not monitor or endorse the material on them. We cannot accept any liability in relation to any such other websites or in relation to any material or information appearing on them or which you may otherwise come across after leaving our site by way of a hypertext link or any other means.

This website or any part of it (or any websites that are linked to this website) may not be compatible with your browser or computer configuration and we make no warranty that it is. We make no warranty that your access to our website will be uninterrupted, timely or error free. It is your responsibility to ensure you carry out sufficient checks (including virus checks) to satisfy your particular requirements. 

User Reviews  
Occasionally, we may allow users to upload comments, videos, photographs, reviews, blog entries and other material in relation to travel or other holiday services. Where you upload such materials, you disclaim any proprietary or other rights you may have in the materials, and agree that such materials can be freely used by the Company for any reason whatsoever, without your permission.

You agree that, at the date of posting, the material submitted by you is appropriate and accurate. You warrant that the material is not misleading, defamatory, untrue, malicious, offensive or abusive. You agree that you will not post any information or material that is owned by another third party without their express authority to do so.

You agree to indemnify the Company for the full amount of all damages, losses, costs and expenses in (including legal costs) in relation to claims brought by any third party against the Company arising out of or in connection with breach of these Conditions in relation to the materials.

The Company reserves the right to refuse to post or remove (without notice) any materials for any reason at its sole discretion. 

Law and Jurisdiction  
Access to this website is conditional on your agreement that all information contained in it and all matters which arise between you and us will be governed by English law. Access is further conditional on your agreement that any dispute or matter which arises between you and us will be dealt with by the Courts of England and Wales only to the exclusion of the Courts of any other country.

If any exclusion(s) or limitation(s) contained in these Conditions is found, in whole or part, to be unlawful, void or for any other reason unenforceable for any purpose(s), that exclusion(s) or limitation(s) or the part(s) in question shall be deemed severable and omitted from these Conditions for that purpose / those purposes. Such omission shall not affect the validity, effectiveness or enforceability of the other provisions of these Conditions.

We may alter these terms and conditions at any time. If we do so, all subsequent use of our website will be governed by the newer version. You must check these terms and conditions regularly.

Updated: March 2015
